{
  "title": "2.7",
  "definitions": {
    "PROTEST": {
      "word": "PROTEST",
      "phonetic": "(prO-test')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to object to, talk against, disapprove of </p><p>PROTEST is a word that has undergone a complete change of meaning. PROTEST used to mean <i class=“def-ital\">to speak</i> for something.  This use is still found in the expression “to PROTEST your innocence\"—that is, to declare or speak in favor of your innocence. Now, however, PROTEST usually means to <i class=“def-ital\">speak against</i> something. </p><p>“The loser PROTESTED the decision against him.” </p><p>“The college students PROTESTED against the war.” </p><p>“The workers PROTESTED that they weren’t paid enough.” </p><p>PROTEST is also a noun. </p><p>“They ignored our PROTESTS and cut down the tree anyway.”</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">pro-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "ISOLATED": {
      "word": "ISOLATED",
      "phonetic": "(Is'-ÔøΩIAt-id)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">alone, solitary, apart </p><p>ISOLATED comes from a Latin word meaning <i class=“def-ital\">island</i>. Someone or something that is ISOLATED is cut off, like an island, from other persons or things. </p><p>“We live on a very ISOLATED farm. There’s no one else for miles around.” </p><p>“The doctors said the patient should be kept ISOLATED so that he doesn’t give the disease to anyone else.” </p><p>To ISOLATE something is to put or keep it apart from others. </p><p>“We tried to ISOLATE the problems and solve them one by one.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: ISOLATE, v., ISOLATION, n.</p>"
    },
    "DEDICATED": {
      "word": "DEDICATED",
      "phonetic": "(ded'-ÔøΩkA-tid)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">devoted, committed, zealous </p><p>To DEDICATE something is to devote it to a particular use, person, or goal. </p><p>“She DEDICATED the book to her parents.” </p><p>“He DEDICATED his life to finding a cure for the common cold.” </p><p>Someone who is DEDICATED is devoted to a cause or a purpose. </p><p>“She is a very DEDICATED musician. She practices many hours every day.” </p><p>“They are DEDICATED to proving their father’s innocence.” </p><p>“There aren’t enough DEDICATED men in the party. Too many of them just don’t seem to care.\"</p><p> Other forms of the word: DEDICATE, v., DEDICATION, n.</p>"
    },
    "FLAWLESS": {
      "word": "FLAWLESS",
      "phonetic": "(flo'-lis)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">perfect, faultless </p><p>A FLAW is a faulty part of something, like a crack in a dish or an imperfection in a jewel. FLAWLESS means “having no FLAW.”  </p><p>“The diamond was FLAWLESS. I have never seen such a perfect stone.” </p><p>“His FLAWLESS reputation was spoiled by that one stupid act.” </p><p>“Donna memorized the poem and then recited it FLAWLESSLY to the class.” </p><p>Many people choose <i class=“def-ital\">bad</i> as the meaning of FLAWLESS. Bad is just about the opposite in meaning of FLAWLESS. People who choose it perhaps know what a FLAW is, but do not know what the suffix <i class=“def-ital\">-less</i> means. </p><p>Other forms of the word: FLAW, n., FLAWLESSLY, adv.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-less</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "DISRUPT": {
      "word": "DISRUPT",
      "phonetic": "(dis-ruhpt')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to break up, throw into disorder </p><p> The <i class=“def-ital\">rupt</i> part of the word means break. It is also found in words like <i class=“def-ital\">interrupt</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">rupture</i>. To DISRUPT something is to break it apart, to destroy the way it normally works. Very often the word suggests that this is only happening for a short time. </p><p>“The electrical storm DISRUPTED telephone service for several hours.” </p><p>“His angry speech DISRUPTED the conference.” </p><p>“Her attempt to teach the class was totally DISRUPTED by the noise outside.” </p><p>“The painters DISRUPTED our office completely. We didn’t know where to find anything, where to sit, or what to do.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: DISRUPTION, n., DISRUPTIVE, adj.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">dis-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "FULFILL": {
      "word": "FULFILL",
      "phonetic": "(ful-fil')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to carry out, complete, satisfy, accomplish </p><p>To FULFILL originally meant what it sounds like: to <i class=“def-ital\">fill up</i>, <i class=“def-ital\">make full</i>. It is no longer used in this way. Today it means to <i class=“def-ital\">do</i> something <i class=“def-ital\">fully</i>, to <i class=“def-ital\">complete</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">accomplish</i> it. </p><p>“Jane FULFILLED her promise to complete the job on time.” </p><p>“Alan has FULFILLED all the requirements for becoming a lifeguard.” </p><p>“This product FULFILLED all our expectations. It is just what we wanted.”</p>"
    },
    "HORDE": {
      "word": "HORDE",
      "phonetic": "(hord)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a crowd, mob, throng, swarm </p><p>A HORDE was originally a wandering tribe of Mongols (an Asian people). Today HORDE is used about any large number of people or things, especially when they are rough or savage. </p><p>“HORDES of fans pushed against the gates of the stadium screaming to be let in.” </p><p>“A HORDE of children tramped through the house, leaving their dirty fingerprints on everything.”</p>"
    },
    "INTERNAL": {
      "word": "INTERNAL",
      "phonetic": "(in-tern'-ÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">inner, interior </p><p>INTERNAL means “having to do with the inside” of something, <i class=“def-ital\">inner</i>.  INTERNAL injuries are injuries suffered inside the body. </p><p>“The president claimed the foreign government was interfering in the INTERNAL affairs of his country.” </p><p>“They carefully removed the cover to get at the INTERNAL parts of the machine.” </p><p>The opposite of INTERNAL is <i class=“def-ital\">external</i>, which means <i class=“def-ital\">outside</i>, <i class=“def-ital\">outer</i>. See <i class=“def-ital\">ex</i> under Prefixes.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">in-</i>, under Prefixes.",
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">ex</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "JUNCTION": {
      "word": "JUNCTION",
      "phonetic": "(juhngk'-shÔøΩn)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a joining, meeting place, union, connection </p><p>A JUNCTION is a joining, a coming together of two or more things. A JUNCTION is also a place where the joining occurs. </p><p>“They built a town at the JUNCTION of the two railroad lines\"—that is, where the two lines met and crossed. The most popular wrong answer on the Pretest is <i class=“def-ital\">dividing</i>, which is an opposite of JUNCTION.</p>"
    },
    "NUISANCE": {
      "word": "NUISANCE",
      "phonetic": "(nUs-ÔøΩns)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a bother, annoyance </p><p>A NUISANCE is a person or thing that causes trouble or worry to others. </p><p>“This table is in everyone’s way. It’s nothing but a NUISANCE.” </p><p>“That boy is making a NUISANCE of himself, teasing his sister while she’s trying to do her homework.” </p><p>“The hole in the sidewalk wasn’t really dangerous, but it was a NUISANCE for us to have to walk around it all the time.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Complaint</i> is the most popular wrong answer. A NUISANCE is likely to cause people to complain, but is not the <i class=“def-ital\">complaint</i> itself.</p>"
    },
    "LOYAL": {
      "word": "LOYAL",
      "phonetic": "(loy'-ÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">faithful, true, devoted </p><p>To be LOYAL is to be devoted or faithful to a person, cause, or ideal. </p><p>“The brave soldier was LOYAL to his country and would not reveal military secrets even under torture.” </p><p>“The LOYAL dog jumped into the river to save its drowning master.” </p><p>LOYALTY, the noun form of the word, is the quality of being faithful. </p><p>“We admired the child’s constant LOYALTY to her aged father.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: LOYALTY, n.</p>"
    },
    "POSSESS": {
      "word": "POSSESS",
      "phonetic": "(pÔøΩzes')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to have, own </p><p>To POSSESS something is to <i class=“def-ital\">have</i> it. </p><p>“She POSSESSES great wealth.” </p><p>“He POSSESSES a lot of charm.” </p><p>“This coin POSSESSES little value.” </p><p>POSSESSION is the owning or having of something. </p><p>“He came into POSSESSION of the painting.” </p><p>POSSESSIONS are things which someone has. </p><p>“All her POSSESSIONS were destroyed in the fire.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: POSSESSION, n., POSSESSIVE, adj.</p>"
    },
    "DISTRESS": {
      "word": "DISTRESS",
      "phonetic": "(dis-tres')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to trouble, upset, disturb, bother </p><p>To DISTRESS someone is to cause him pain or sorrow. </p><p>“It DISTRESSES me to see you so unhappy.” </p><p>“She was DISTRESSED by the news of her husband’s disappearance.” </p><p>“We have received DISTRESSING news about an airplane crash.” </p><p>DISTRESS is also a noun, meaning suffering or <i class=“def-ital\">misfortune</i>. </p><p>“The ship radioed that it was in DISTRESS and was in danger of sinking.” </p><p>“He tried to relieve Susan’s DISTRESS by telling her that everything would turn out all right in the end.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: DISTRESSING, adj.</p>"
    },
    "PRECIOUS": {
      "word": "PRECIOUS",
      "phonetic": "(presh'-ÔøΩs)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">valuable, costly, priceless, dear </p><p>PRECIOUS is related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">price</i>. Something that is PRECIOUS has a high price, is of great value. </p><p>“These PRECIOUS jewels are worth a fortune to us.” </p><p>PRECIOUS is also used about things which are of such value that they cannot be bought. </p><p>“My children are PRECIOUS to me. I wouldn’t do anything to harm them.” </p><p>“We have a few PRECIOUS hours in which to find the bomb before it goes off.” </p><p>Many people choose <i class=“def-ital\">rare</i> as the right answer. Often something is PRECIOUS because it is <i class=“def-ital\">rare</i>, but the two words do not have the same meaning.</p>"
    },
    "PURSUE": {
      "word": "PURSUE",
      "phonetic": "(pÔøΩr-sU')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to chase, follow, go after </p><p>To PURSUE something is to follow after it. You can PURSUE anything: a car, a person, success, happiness, and so on. </p><p>“The police PVRSUED the escaped prisoner.” </p><p>“He was PURSUED by shouts as he left the meeting.” </p><p>“All people should have the right to PURSUE happiness.” </p><p>PURSUIT is the noun from PURSUE. </p><p>“Everyone joined in the PURSUIT of the criminal.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: PURSUIT, n.</p>"
    }
  },
  "id": "7",
  "exercises": [
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "They PROTEST the decision.",
          "answers": [
            "hate",
            "agree with",
            "ask for",
            "object to",
            "forget"
          ],
          "word": "PROTEST",
          "correct": "object to"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They kept him ISOLATED.",
          "answers": [
            "quiet",
            "unhappy",
            "nearby",
            "warm",
            "alone"
          ],
          "word": "ISOLATED",
          "correct": "alone"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DEDICATED people.",
          "answers": [
            "disloyal",
            "intelligent",
            "displeased",
            "devoted",
            "obedient"
          ],
          "word": "DEDICATED",
          "correct": "devoted"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FLAWLESS performance.",
          "answers": [
            "perfect",
            "suitable",
            "illegal",
            "bad",
            "unbelievable"
          ],
          "word": "FLAWLESS",
          "correct": "perfect"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DISRUPT the meeting.",
          "answers": [
            "break up",
            "shock",
            "avoid",
            "arrange",
            "call off"
          ],
          "word": "DISRUPT",
          "correct": "break up"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FULFILL the obligation.",
          "answers": [
            "forget",
            "accept",
            "complete",
            "add to",
            "put off"
          ],
          "word": "FULFILL",
          "correct": "complete"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A HORDE of them.",
          "answers": [
            "dozen",
            "crowd",
            "few",
            "bag",
            "pair"
          ],
          "word": "HORDE",
          "correct": "crowd"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTERNAL signs.",
          "answers": [
            "outside",
            "invisible",
            "obvious",
            "inner",
            "necessary"
          ],
          "word": "INTERNAL",
          "correct": "inner"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The JUNCTION of the rivers.",
          "answers": [
            "end",
            "width",
            "dividing",
            "beginning",
            "joining"
          ],
          "word": "JUNCTION",
          "correct": "joining"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "General NUISANCE.",
          "answers": [
            "help",
            "knowledge",
            "bother",
            "complaint",
            "evil"
          ],
          "word": "NUISANCE",
          "correct": "bother"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LOYAL men.",
          "answers": [
            "smart",
            "faithful",
            "funny",
            "noble",
            "brave"
          ],
          "word": "LOYAL",
          "correct": "faithful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They POSSESS little.",
          "answers": [
            "have",
            "advance",
            "need",
            "spend",
            "lose"
          ],
          "word": "POSSESS",
          "correct": "have"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It will DISTRESS him.",
          "answers": [
            "change",
            "kill",
            "trouble",
            "tire",
            "thrill"
          ],
          "word": "DISTRESS",
          "correct": "trouble"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PRECIOUS things.",
          "answers": [
            "pretty",
            "rare",
            "new",
            "valuable",
            "useless"
          ],
          "word": "PRECIOUS",
          "correct": "valuable"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Will they PURSUE us?",
          "answers": [
            "find",
            "chase",
            "fight",
            "lead",
            "promise"
          ],
          "word": "PURSUE",
          "correct": "chase"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-one",
      "id": "pretest"
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do people usually PROTEST when they win a prize?",
          "word": "PROTEST",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "When a mother kisses her baby, is she ISOLATING it?",
          "word": "ISOLATED",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a DEDICATED teacher be likely to spend extra time helping her students?",
          "word": "DEDICATED",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would an artist like to paint a FLAWLESS picture?",
          "word": "FLAWLESS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would the noise of a jackhammer DISRUPT a concert?",
          "word": "DISRUPT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If you keep a promise, have you FULFILLED it?",
          "word": "FULFILL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a HORDE usually be peaceful and friendly?",
          "word": "HORDE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is your hair an INTERNAL part of you?",
          "word": "INTERNAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could your wrist be called the JUNCTION between your hand and your arm?",
          "word": "JUNCTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people like NUISANCES?",
          "word": "NUISANCE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a boss want to hire workers who would be LOYAL to the company?",
          "word": "LOYAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a person POSSESS a sense of humor?",
          "word": "POSSESS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it DISTRESSING to win a race?",
          "word": "DISTRESS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are most pencils PRECIOUS?",
          "word": "PRECIOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do you always catch something that you PURSUE?",
          "word": "PURSUE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {}
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "They PROTESTED that there wasn't enough time to do what he wanted them to do.",
          "word": "PROTEST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Hermits are people who avoid the company of others and would rather be ISOLATED.",
          "word": "ISOLATED",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The mayor DEDICATED the new city hall to the people of the city.",
          "word": "DEDICATED",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Jack made only a couple of mistakes in his FLAWLESS performance.",
          "word": "FLAWLESS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The volcano looked like it was going to DISRUPT at any minute.",
          "word": "DISRUPT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He FULFILLED the cup to overflowing.",
          "word": "FULFILL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The sudden arrival of HORDES of insects ruined the barbecue.",
          "word": "HORDE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Bob opened up the machine to get at its INTERNAL parts.",
          "word": "INTERNAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "This set of railroad tracks had many JUNCTIONS with other sets of tracks.",
          "word": "JUNCTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The dog became such a NUISANCE that finally we had to give it away.",
          "word": "NUISANCE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Benedict Arnold showed his LOYALTY to the United States by giving secrets to the British.",
          "word": "LOYAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He POSSESSED a magic ring that could make him invisible.",
          "word": "POSSESS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The teacher DISTRESSED to them the importance of studying hard.",
          "word": "DISTRESS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His weekends are PRECIOUS to him. He won't let anyone disturb them.",
          "word": "PRECIOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He didn't care whom he hurt in his PURSUIT of great wealth.",
          "word": "PURSUE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "PROTEST",
          "answers": [
            "give up",
            "complain",
            "disapprove"
          ],
          "word": "PROTEST",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ISOLATED",
          "answers": [
            "apart",
            "different",
            "alone"
          ],
          "word": "ISOLATED",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DEDICATED",
          "answers": [
            "committed",
            "smart",
            "determined"
          ],
          "word": "DEDICATED",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FLAWLESS",
          "answers": [
            "errorless",
            "difficult",
            "perfect"
          ],
          "word": "FLAWLESS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DISRUPT",
          "answers": [
            "stop",
            "destroy",
            "dislike"
          ],
          "word": "DISRUPT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FULFILL",
          "answers": [
            "complete",
            "excite",
            "satisfy"
          ],
          "word": "FULFILL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HORDE",
          "answers": [
            "crowd",
            "mob",
            "criminal"
          ],
          "word": "HORDE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTERNAL",
          "answers": [
            "inner",
            "everlasting",
            "hidden"
          ],
          "word": "INTERNAL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "JUNCTION",
          "answers": [
            "meeting",
            "connection",
            "difference"
          ],
          "word": "JUNCTION",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "NUISANCE",
          "answers": [
            "trouble",
            "anger",
            "obstacle"
          ],
          "word": "NUISANCE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LOYAL",
          "answers": [
            "united",
            "faithful",
            "devoted"
          ],
          "word": "LOYAL",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "POSSESS",
          "answers": [
            "need",
            "own",
            "buy"
          ],
          "word": "POSSESS",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DISTRESS",
          "answers": [
            "silence",
            "sorrow",
            "pain"
          ],
          "word": "DISTRESS",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PRECIOUS",
          "answers": [
            "important",
            "old",
            "expensive"
          ],
          "word": "PRECIOUS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PURSUE",
          "answers": [
            "seek",
            "follow",
            "choose"
          ],
          "word": "PURSUE",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-all",
      "id": 3
    }
  ]
}